Guide to the Cynthia Harrison feminist document collection, 1921-2008 MS1005.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Cynthia Harrison feminist documents collection
1921-2008
1960-1980
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS1005.UA
20.5 Linear Feet
This collection consists of articles, newsletters, children's books, lecture notes, personal notes, and personal correspondence, as well as photocopies of primary sources such as newspaper articles, press releases, reports and memoranda related to GWU Professor Cynthia Ellen Harrison's research and personal involvement in the women's rights movement. Items date from the early 1920's to the mid 1990's, with the bulk of the material dating to between 1960 and 1980. Cynthia Ellen Harrison is a retired Associate Professor of History, Women's Studies, and Public Policy at The George Washington University. Since 1994 Professor Harrison served the University as a teacher and an active researcher in US women's political history.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of articles, newsletters, children's books, lecture notes, personal notes, and personal correspondence, as well as photocopies of primary sources such as newspaper articles, press releases, reports and memoranda related to GWU Professor Cynthia Ellen Harrison's research and personal involvement in the women's rights movement. Items date from the early 1920's to the mid 1990's, with the bulk of the material dating to between 1960 and 1980.
This collection was largely produced and/or used by Professor Harrison as part of her research for her 1988 book On Account of Sex: The Politics of Women's Issues, 1945-1968. Harrison created copies of original documents from various archives, presidential libraries, and government records recording the political history of the women's movement from the mid 1940's to the 1960's. Many of the documents accessed through the records of federal agencies may no longer be easily available to researchers, making Harrison's copies a potentially vital resource for historians. Harrison's notes and drafts synthesize and comment upon these primary sources, providing insight into the processes of drafting and publishing her book. Other materials highlight Harrison's personal commitment to the second-wave feminist movement, including letters of complaint to companies with sexist advertisements and business policies, and a collection of feminist publications that Harrison subscribed to.
Harrison's collection includes materials documenting the history of the Equal Rights Amendment and the Equal Pay Act, as well as the activities of the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) and the US Women's Bureau. Of particular interest are oral histories by PCSW members Esther Peterson (later director of the Women's Bureau) and Marguerite Rawalt. Other topics covered include the activities of local, grassroots feminist movements, women's reproductive rights and health education, sexism in American culture, and children's education and exposure to stereotyped gender roles.
Historical or Biographical Note
Cynthia Ellen Harrison is a retired Associate Professor of History, Women's Studies, and Public Policy at The George Washington University. Since 1994 Professor Harrison served the University as a teacher and an active researcher in US women's political history. Harrison previously served as the Chief of the Federal Judicial History Office from 1988 to 1994, at the American Historical Association/American Political Science Association from 1982 to 1988, and as a research fellow at The Brookings Institute from 1979 to 1982. Harrison received her PhD in American History from Columbia University in 1982. From 1968 to 1972 Harrison worked as a librarian at first the Brooklyn Public Library, and later the McMaster University Library in Ontario, Canada.
Professor Harrison's publications include a large number of articles on the history of the US women's rights movement, two reference works on primary sources available to researchers in women's history, and a 1988 book, On Account of Sex: The Politics of Women's Issues, 1945 to 1968.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Professor Cynthia Ellen Harrison, 2014, (2014.022)
Restrictions on Access
This collection is open for research.
Collection Organization
Organized into 12 series: Activism; Archival citations; Children's books; Equal pay; Equal Rights Amendment (ERA); Harrison's desk; Mailings, magazines, newsletters; Manuscript research; Oral history; Political involvement; Oversized boxes; and Women's issues resources
Feminists; Women's rights; Feminist theory; Politics and culture -- United States -- 20th century
- Activism, 1971-1977; Series 1 (Box 1)
  Arrangement Note
  Arranged alphabetically
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains letters of complaint written by Cynthia Harrison to companies with sex discriminatory business practices or sexist advertisements. These letters, and replies from the companies, were sent largely during the mid-1970's and demonstrate Professor Harrison's personal commitment and activism in the women's rights movement.
  - A. & S. (Abraham & Strauss) discriminatory alterations policy, 1974; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Additional Listings, 1973; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bamberger's discriminatory alterations policy, 1973-1976; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - BankAmericard discriminatory credit policy, 1974; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bloomingdale's discriminatory credit policy, 1974; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Credit applications 1974, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - First National Iron Bank discriminatory credit policy, 1974; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - GEICO complaint, 1973-1975; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter campaign against sexist ads & congratulatory letters to companies that portray women positively, 1971-1975; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Saks Fifth Avenue discriminatory credit policy, 1973; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - SEARS discriminatory credit policy, 1973-1976; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stern's discriminatory alterations policy, 1973-1974; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Verona Board of Education, 1972-1974; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Washington Area Feminist Federal Credit Union, 1976-1977; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Archival citations, 1946-1980; Series 2 (Box 1)
  This series consists of copy orders and citations from archives and libraries that Professor Harrison visited during the late 1970's in the process of collecting research material for her book. The list of archives and resources accessed by Harrison demonstrate her research process and provide insight into her writing.
  - Congressional record, Xerox order, notes, citations, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - DOL-CSC, ann. reports, undated; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower Library, Xerox order, finding aid, 1975; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Emanuel Cellar (EC), access granted. See cards for full citation of numbered Xeroxes, 1978 April 26; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Emma Guffey Miller (EGM), Xerox order, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Esther Peterson (Schlesinger) woman, political, NCCWR, Xerox order, 1979; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Esther Peterson (Schlesinger), Xerox Order, 1975; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Griffiths, Martha (MG) 1957-1967, Xerox order, 1978; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Green, Edith (EG), Xerox order, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hattie Smith (HS), citations, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - HEW (labeled, not indexed), Xerox order, access granted, 1978; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - HSTL, Xerox order, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - John F. Kennedy Library I & II, Xerox order, undated; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Katherine Norris (KN), Xerox order, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Katherine P. Ellickson (KPE), source locations, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Katie S. Louchheim (KSL), access granted, 1976 December 7; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - LBJ Library 1-22, Xerox order, 1978; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - LBJ Library 23-36, Xerox order, 1978; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - LBJ Library 37-63, Xerox order, 1978; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - LBJ Library 37-63, Xerox order, 1978; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - LBJ Library Department of Labor, microfilm reel 16, 17, & 20; citations, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - LBJ Library Department of Labor, microfilm reel 25; citations, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - LBJ Library oral history, Xerox order, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Leopold, Alice K. (AKL), Xerox order, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Mary Anderson (MA), Xerox order, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Miller, Frieda (FM), Xerox order, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Morse, Wayne (WM), Xerox order, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - NWP papers (National Women's Party), citations, 1980; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Neuberger, Maurine (MN), Xerox order, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - New York Times Index, MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Price, Margaret B. (MBP), Xerox order, 1978; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - RG86 (Women's Bureau), CACSW papers (NA), Xerox order, 1980; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - RG 174 I-III & Tobin, Xerox order, 1979; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - RG 174 IV, Xerox order, 1979; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - RG 174 V & VI, 1979; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - RG 174 VII et. al., citations, 1979; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - RG 174 VIII-XI, 1979; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor I & II, Xerox order, 1946-1974; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Schlesinger Library subject file ERA 1949-1950, Xerox order, 1979; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Simchak papers (Detroit), Xerox order, correspondence, 1979-1980; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - St. George, Katherine (KStG), Xerox order, 1979; MS1005.UA (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - The Eleanor Roosevlet Center at Val-Kill Brochure, Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Children's books, 1970-1977; Series 3 (Box 2)
  This series contains a selection of feminist children's books and publications documenting the pervasiveness of sexual stereotyping in mainstream children's literature. These publications date from the early to mid-1970's.
  - "ABC Workbook" by Jean Mangi, The Feminist Press, 1975; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "A Train for Jane" by Norma Klein, The Feminist Press, 1974; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Carlotta and the Scientist" by Patricia Riley Lenthall, Lollipop Power, Inc., 1973; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Challenge to become a Doctor The Story of Elizabeth Blackwell" by Leah Lurie Heyn, The Feminist Press, 1971; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Children's books, 1970-1974; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Did You Ever" by Paula Goldsmid, Lollipop Power, Inc., 1971; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Dragon and the Doctor" by Barbara Danish, The Feminist Press, 1971; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Exactly Like Me" by Lynn Phillips, Lollipop Power, Inc., 1972; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Firegirl" by Gibson Rich, The Feminist Press, 1972; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Grown Ups Cry Too" by Nancy Hazen, Lollipop Power, Inc., 1973; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Jenny's Secret Place" by Sara Evans Boyte, Lollipop Power, Inc., 1970; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Jo, Flo and Yolanda" by Carol de Poix, Lollipop Power, Inc., 1973; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Joshua's Day" by Sandra Lucas Surowiecki, Lollipop Power, Inc., 1972; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "The King Who Rained" by Fred Gwynne, Young Reader's Press, Inc., 1970; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "The Magic Hat" by Kim Westmith Chapman, Lollipop Power, Inc., 1973; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Martin's Father" by Margrit Eichler, Lollipop Power, Inc., 1971; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Non-sexist book lists, 1970-1977; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Nothing But a Dog" by Bobbi Katz, The Feminist Press, 1972; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "The Sheep Book" by Carmen Goodyear, Lollipop Power, Inc., 1972; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Equal pay, 1943-1980; Series 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Box 2)
  This series contains photocopies of primary source material (reports, memoranda, drafts of bills, etc.), publications, and some of Harrison's personal notes on the history of the Equal Pay Act of 1963. The bulk of the material dates from the 1940's to the late 1960's. Much of the material orginated from the Women's Bureau.
  - Equal Pay Act pre-1945, 1943-1979; MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Equal Pay Act 1945-1952, MS1005.UA (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Equal Pay 1945-1960, 1944-1955; MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Equal Pay Act 1953-1960, 1953-1968; MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Equal Pay Act 1961-1963, MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Equal Pay Act 1964-, 1964-1974; MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Equal Pay & Women in Labor Unions, 1956-1980; MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - EPA - History of the Bennett Amendment; correspondence & newsclips summer, 1965, MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - EPA - Notebook Material: September, 1963, MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - EPA - Notebook material: May - July 1963, MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - EPA - Notebook material: March-April 1963, MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - EPA - Notebook material: February, 1963, MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - EPA - Notebook material: January: 1963, MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - EPA - Notebook material: 1962, MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - EPA - Notebook material: "Equal Pay for Equal Work: Federal Legislature Activity 1945-1962" by J.P. Eavner December 14, 1962, MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Manual on Pay Equity: Raising Wages for Women's Work, conference on alternative state and local policies, Committee on Pay Equity, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Testimony - EPA 3/78, 1978 March (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Women's Bureau - Supplementary 1953-1960 Equal Pay [1/2], 1953-1957; MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Women's Bureau Supplementary 1953-1960 Equal Pay [2/2], 1955-1960; MS1005.UA (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Equal Rights Amendment (ERA), 1921-1979; Series 5 (Box 4, Box 5, Box 6)
  This series contains photocopies of primary source material (reports, memoranda, correspondence, etc.), and publications on the history of and debate surrounding the Equal Rights Amendment. The bulk of the material dates from the mid-1940's to the 1970's.
  - Congressional Digest - ERA controversy, 1977; MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Congressional record, Senate proceedings & debates (ERA), 1972 March 22; MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ERA pre-1945, 1923-1944; MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - ERA 1945-1952 alternatives besides status bill, MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - ERA 1945-1952 congressional debate, MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - ERA 1945-1952 congressional opponents, MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - ERA 1945-1952 congressional supporters, 1945-1950; MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - ERA pre-1945 Department of Labor response, 1943-1944; MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - ERA 1945-1953, MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - ERA 1954, MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - ERA 1955-1956, MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - ERA 1957-1958, MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - ERA 1959, MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - ERA 1960, 1959-1960; MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - ERA 1964 [1/2], 1963-1966; MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - ERA 1964 [2/2], 1966-1970; MS1005.UA (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - ERA 1945-1952 Department of Labor (DOL) response, 1943-1949; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - ERA 1945-1952 Eleanor Roosevelt, 1944-1952; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - ERA 1945-1952 executive response, departments, 1949; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - ERA 1945-1952 executive response, white house, MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ERA 1945-1952 labor organizations (anti), MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - ERA 1945-1952, 1946-1949; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - ERA 1945-1952 Media, 1945-1951; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - ERA 1953-1960 misc., MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - ERA pre-1945 organizations (letters), 1921-1944; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - ERA 1945-1952 organizations (letters), 1943-1952; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - ERA 1945-1952 organizations, National Committee to Defeat the Unequal Rights Amendment, 1944-1950; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - ERA 1945-1952 organizations, National Women's Party, 1945-1950; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - ERA 1945-1950 saving clauses, MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - ERA pre-1945 WB response, 1943-1944; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - ERA 1945-1952 WB response, 1945-1951; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - ERA 1945-1952 Women's Status Bill (General), 1946-1950; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - The ERA & States, 1972-1976; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - ERA & the homemaker, 1976; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - ERA extension resolution, 1977-1978; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - ERA fact sheets, background info & rebuttals, 1949-1974; MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - ERA fliers, brochures, etc., MS1005.UA (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - ERAmerica letters, 1975-1979; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - ERAmerica press releases to the media, 1976 February 25; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - ERA myths & folklore, ERAmerica, 1976; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ERA New York Times 1942-1960, MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The ERA - Senator Ervin's minority report and the Yale Law Journal Citizen's Advisory Council on the Status of Women, 1972 July; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - ERA speaking notes, MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ERA-VA, 1974-1978; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ERA vigil, 1976 June 29; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Good Causes and Lost Causes: Requiem for ERA by Marion K. Saunders in The New Republic, 1975 November 29; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - GW ERA News, GW Students for the Equal Rights Amendment, 1976 June; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Harrison's draft for the pro-ERA Feminist Homemaker flier, 1976 April 12; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hayden papers-ERA, 1943-1953; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - The Impact of an ERA on the Financial Rights of Married Women: An Overview, Anne K. Bingaman, 1975; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - International Women's Year Commission report on ERAmerica formation, 1976 January 15; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - McNamara papers-ERA, 1957-1961; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - The Phyllis Schlafly Report, 1976 February; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Congressional Research Service: The Proposed Equal Rights Amendment, Karen Keesling, analyst, 1978 March 9; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Interpretation of the ERA in Accordance With Legislative History, Citizen's Advisory Council on the Status of Women, 1974 January; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Ten Things the ERA Will Do For You; Ten Things the ERA Won't Do For You, MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Testimonies: ERA, 1976; MS1005.UA (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - "What Happens if this Man Leaves the Picture..." Common Cause, ERA (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - "You'll Probably Think I'm Stupid" ERA, Martha Weinman Lear in the New York Times Magazine, 1976 April 11 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Harrison's desk, 1967-1995; Series 6 (Box 8, Box 7)
  This series consists of correspondence, speech drafts, notes and collected articles and publicity releases for Harrison's "Women's Movement Media: A Source Guide." These materials were almost entirely produced by or for Professor Cynthia Harrison herself durin gthe 1970's and early 1980's.
  - 12 days of Christmas parody, 1972; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Amusing items, 1967; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence [1/2], 1978-1983; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence [2/2], 1982-1986; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Community property bill, 1969-1978; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Coping with Conflict: Reproductive Choices and Community Controversy - brochure, League of Women Voters Education Fund, 1986; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Discrimination in the workplace [1/2], 1982-1988; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Discrimination in the workplace [2/2], 1982-1988; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Feminist products, 1983-1995; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - GWU talk, 1982; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Harrison manuscript intro, 1973-1975; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Harrison speech draft, MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Jewish newspaper clippings, 1975-1980; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Jill Ruckelshaw's speech, 1975 September 12; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - New York Times strike articles, 1970-1981; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Office of Education official papers, 1978-1979; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Preface, MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Remarks on Equality" Liz Carpenter, Media VII conference, 1976 June 8; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Richie's letters, 1972-1983; MS1005.UA (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - TV program, 1974; MS1005.UA (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Women's health, 1982-1985; MS1005.UA (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Women's liberation correspondence [1/4], MS1005.UA (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Women's liberation correspondence [2/4], 1970-1972; MS1005.UA (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Women's liberation correspondence [3/4], 1973-1975; MS1005.UA (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Women's liberation correspondence [4/4], 1976-1981; MS1005.UA (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Women's Movement Media: A Source Guide, correspondence, 1972-1979; MS1005.UA (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Women's Movement Media - Publicity, 1974-1976; MS1005.UA (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1974 maps, MS1005.UA (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Mailings, magazines, newsletters, 1968-1995; Series 7 (Box 19, Box 20, Box 17, Box 18, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 12, Box 11, Box 10, Box 9, Box 16, Box 15, Box 14, Box 13)
  This series consists of mailings and publications from women's rights organizations that Professor Harrison subscribed to during the 1970's to early 1990's.
  - Ain't I A Woman?, 1972-1973; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Alert Women's Legislative Review, 1973 June; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority Heritage Series booklets, 1968-1971; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - American Council on Education newsletter, 1987 January 14; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Aphra [1/6], 1971-1972; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Aphra [2/6], 1972; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Aphra [3/6], 1972-1973; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Aphra [4/6], 1973-1974; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Aphra [5/6], 1974; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Aphra [6/6], 1974-1975; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Association for the Study of Abortion (ASA), 1973; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Association of American Law Schools newsletter, 1972-1973; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Association of Women in Science (AWIS) newsletter, 1973; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Aurora, 1971-1972; Series 7 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Boston Women's Health Collective, 1987; Series 7 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Breakthrough, Interstate Association of Commissions on the Status of Women, 1972-1973; MS1005.UA (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Canadian Federation of University Women (CFUW) News/Chronicle, 1972-1973; MS1005.UA (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Canadian Newsletter of Research on Women, 1972-1973; MS1005.UA (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Caucus for Women in Statistics, 1973; MS1005.UA (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - CCWHP Newsletter, Coordinating Committee on Women in the Historical Profession, 1973-1987; MS1005.UA (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Center for Continuing Education Newsletter, University of MI, 1973; MS1005.UA (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Change: A working woman's newspaper, 1973; MS1005.UA (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - City of Alexandria, VA, status of women, 1975; MS1005.UA (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Civil Liberties Alert, newsletter of the American Civil Liberties Union, Washington office, 1983-1989; MS1005.UA (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Clearinghouse for Feminist Media, 1972 April; MS1005.UA (Box 10, Folder 11)